Clara E. Sipprell Papers
Clara E. Sipprell Papers
1915-1970
Sipprell, Clara E. (Clara Estelle), 1885-1975.
93 linear ft.
Papers of the American photographer. Original photographs, arranged as character studies, landscapes, portraits, and still life studies. Correspondence (1929-1970), clippings, interviews, photographs of her. Portraits of Louis Adamic, Svetlana Allilueva, Van Wyck Brooks, Pearl S. Buck, Rudolf Bultmann, Charles E. Burchfield, Fyodor Chaliapin, Ralph Adams Cram, W.E.B. Du Bois, Albert Einstein, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, Ralph E. Flanders, Michel Fokine, Robert Frost, Eva Hansl, Roy Harris, Granville Hicks, Malvina Hoffman, Langston Hughes, Robinson Jeffers, Louis Krasner, Serge Koussevitzky, Luigi Lucioni, Emil Ludwig, Edwin Markham, Isamu Noguchi, Maxfield Parrish, Sergei Rachmaninoff, Eleanor Roosevelt, Dane Rudhyar, Ruth St. Denis, Otis Skinner, Ida Tarbell, Howard Thurman, Ridgely Torrence, Hendrik Van Loon, and others
148667
Biographical History
If you would like to download or print this finding aid, we strongly suggest you use this pdf version.
Clara E. Sipprell (1885-1975) was a Canadian-American photographer known for her landscapes and portraits of famous actors, artists, writers and scientists.
Sipprell was born in Ontario, Canada, a posthumous child with five brothers. Her widowed mother had to work to support the family, and Clara lived with her grandparents until she was old enough to go to school. Henry, the next to eldest, went to Buffalo, New York, where he found work and soon drew the rest of the family after him. The eldest boy, Frank, became a photographer and soon had a shop of his own.
Clara spent her free time in her brother's shop. At the age of sixteen she left school and devoted her entire time to what was to become her life's work. For ten years she assisted her brother Frank, learning photographic techniques during the period of the glass plate and platinum paper. When artificial lighting came into use her brother adopted it, but Clara stuck to the old ways. By doing so, she was setting up her own standards and establishing her own ideas of what a photograph should be. She did not use artificial lighting, believing that natural light would give the result she preferred. She did not enlarge, nor did she crop her photographs to manipulate her composition; implicitly the composition must be complete before the picture is made. It is claimed also that she did not retouch her negatives, although there is some evidence in the collection to the contrary.
Her early exhibitions were at the Buffalo Camera Club at a time when its membership was closed to women; one year she won half the prizes offered. Her first New York show was at Teachers College, Columbia University, and in 1915 she opened a studio in Greenwich Village where she shared an apartment with long-time friend Jessica Beers. The work of other New York photographers taught her much, she says; Alfred Stieglitz, Edward Steichen, Dr. Arnold Genthe, Max Weber, Clarence White, Gertrude Kasebier, and Alice Boughton were among them. She became a member of the Pictorial Photographers of America, the Royal Photographic Society of Great Britain, and the Arts Club of Washington.
A Russian friend, Irina Khrabroff, arranged for Sipprell to photograph Stanislavsky's Moscow Art Theatre troupe, the first of a number of seminal opportunities for her. A trip to Vermont opened up further vistas for her, and she engaged a studio in the Connecticut River Valley village of Thetford which she maintained for seventeen summers. In 1923 Irina married Yugoslavian Feodor D. Cekich (alternate spellings in related collections at other repositories include Zekitch and Cekic), through whom Sipprell was introduced to that country as a subject for her photographs. Sipprell and the Cekiches remained close friends and traveling companions for many years. Nina, the child of this marriage, was Sipprell's god-daughter and a frequent subject of her photographs from birth through marriage and motherhood. Sipprell traveled to Sweden in 1928, where her friends arranged access to the Royal Palace and the opportunity to photograph King Gustav and other members of the Swedish royal family.
Many famous personalities came to her studio for portraits, including Albert Einstein, Robert Frost, Edwin Markham, and Pearl Buck. During the 1920s and 1930s, Sipprell's work was recognized in both national and international exhibits which included her work in landscapes and still lifes as well as portraits. One of her cityscapes, "New York-Old and New", was one of the first photographs acquired by the Museum of Modern Art in 1932.
In 1937 Sipprell moved her Vermont summer studio from Thetford Hill to Manchester Center. Shortly thereafter Sipprell met writer and librarian Phyllis Fenner, who became her housemate, traveling companion, and close friend for the next thirty-eight years.
Annual trips to Spain, Portugal, Italy, Greece, Japan, Great Britain, France, and to visit friends in Yugoslavia provided new experiences and new subjects for her camera. A collection of sixty photographs, which included several taken as a result of these trips as well as many portraits of those whom she regarded as the "great ones", was chosen for exhibition at Syracuse University in 1960. Sipprell died in 1975 at the age of 89.
[Much of the above adapted from Elizabeth Gray Vining, "Introduction" to Moment of light: Photographs of Clara Sipprell, New York, John Day Company, 1966. Some information about Nina (Cekich) Strauss Helms taken from obituaries in the Valley News, 28 Feb 2016, and on the Rand-Wilson Funeral Home guest book.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Clara Sipprell Papers consist of correspondence, memorabilia, negatives and proof prints, photographs, and a small amount of miscellaneous material.
Correspondence contains client correspondence and a small amount of personal correspondence, including letters and research materials created by Phyllis Fenner and Antje Lemke.
Memorabilia includes Sipprell's photographic equipment (camera, a lens, and an easel) as well as a studio brochure and business card, two taped interviews with Sipprell, and an assortment of personal photographs.
Negatives and proof prints comprise the bulk of the collection. Note that a given photograph may exist in numerous different negative forms, some created by Sipprell and others created by staff as part of preservation efforts. In addition, many of the negatives have been digitized and are available online. Many are also present as prints (see Photographs, below). To simplify locating all negatives of a person or subject, this section of the inventory lists them in alphabetical order by name of the subject. Children are often listed under the parents' names -- for example, "Lewar, Katherine (son)" -- and wives under the name of their husband (for example, "Smith, Mrs. John").
The collection also contains two hundred and forty original Photographs, 1915-1963, approximately eighty of which appeared in the book Moment of light: Photographs of Clara Sipprell by Elizabeth Gray Vining. These are divided into four series determined by their subject matter; many are also available in various negative forms (see Negatives and proof prints, above).
Character studies of individuals include five prints of Nina Cekich, Miss Sipprell's god-daughter, as well as one of Peter Helms, Nina's son.
Landscape studies include four subseries of United States, Canadian, Vermont, and Yugoslav views.
Portrait studies, the most extensive series in the collection, represent Miss Sipprell's photographs of celebrities, friends and neighbors. Items in this series are listed alphabetically by the last name of the person portrayed, with the exception of royalty which may be located under the given name. When more than one person is portrayed in the same photograph, cross references are provided.
Still life studies contains miscellaneous still lifes.
Prints acquired separately contain works by Sipprell that were donated by others and acquired separately from the rest of the collection. The donors for each item are given in the inventory below.
Miscellaneous materials include articles and clippings about Sipprell, two autochromes, exhibit catalogs, a file index of the Sipprell negatives created by staff at, a framed negative, and a Master's thesis written by Sipprell scholar Mary Kennedy McCabe.
Other Formats Available
Audiocassette use copies of interviews are in the box with the tapes.
Arrangement of the Collection
Boxes 1-48 no longer exist, following the 2020 NEDCC project. The collection begins with Box 49.
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by form. Negatives and proof prints are physically arranged in no particular order, as best suits their preservation needs (for example, nitrate negatives are in vapor-proof packs and stored in freezers). Photographs are divided into four series (character studies, landscape studies, portrait studies, and still lifes); within each series photographs are arranged alphabetically by name (for portraits) or by caption (for others). Prints acquired separately and Miscellaneous materials are arranged alphabetically by form.
Related Material
has the papers of many photographers, including Margaret Bourke-White and others. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Photography; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.; Allilueva, Svetlana, 1926-2011.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Bultmann, Rudolf, 1884-1976.; Burchfield, Charles, 1893-1967.; Chaliapin, Fyodor Ivanovich, 1873-1938.; Cram, Ralph Adams, 1863-1942.; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Flanders, Ralph E. (Ralph Edward), 1880-1970.; Fokine, Michel, 1880-1942.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Hansl, Eva vB. (Eva vom Baur); Harris, Roy, 1898-1979.; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; Hoffman, Malvina, 1887-1966.; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967.; Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962.; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951.; Krasner, Louis, 1903-1995.; Lucioni, Luigi, 1900-1988.; Ludwig, Emil, 1881-1948.; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940.; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-1988.; Parrish, Maxfield, 1870-1966.; Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985.; St. Denis, Ruth, 1880-1968.; Sipprell, Clara E. (Clara Estelle), 1885-1975.; Skinner, Otis, 1858-1942.; Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944.; Thurman, Howard, 1900-1981.; Torrence, Ridgely, 1875-1950.; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944.; Available light photography.; Nature photography.; Photographers -- United States.; Photography -- Equipment and supplies.; Photography, Artistic.; Portrait photography.; Russians -- Portraits.; Still-life photography.; Women photographers -- United States.; Yugoslavs -- Portraits.; Yugoslavia -- Pictorial works.; Yugoslavia -- Description and travel.; Audiotapes.; Autochromes (photographs); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Glass plate negatives.; Negatives (photographs); Photographs.; Portraits.; Sound recordings.; Photographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Items stored in freezer boxes (denoted by "FB") are not accessible to researchers.
Glass plate negatives are currently out for digitization and not accessible to staff or researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, various dates. Some items, gift of Phyllis Fenner. Two photographs, gift of Richard Kremer, 2003. 2007. Audiotapes and other items, gift of Antje Lemke, 1977, 1979, 1980, 1988, 1991. Christensen correspondence, gift of Susan Jowaiszas, 2020.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  If you would like to download or print this inventory, we strongly suggest you use this pdf version.
  - Clients, includes one print, accompanying a letter from a Mr McClellan; 2 folders (Box 70)
  - Personal
    All personal correspondence was donated separately, as noted below.
    - Christensen, Chris, 1970-1974; 1980-1981; letters from Sipprell and Fenner; includes photographs of Sipprell taken by Christensen (Box 70)
      Gift of Susan Jowaiszas, 2020.
    - Fenner, Phyllis, 1964; 1976,; 1982; includes photograph of Sipprell and Fenner; copy of Fenner's will (Box 70)
      Gift of Antje Lemke, 1988.
    - Lemke, Antje, 1959-1963; 1984; includes handwritten draft of a paper or essay about Sipprell; 2 folders (Box 70)
- Memorabilia
  - Autochrome cases, two different sizes, stamped with "Sipprell Studios" (Box 73)
  - Equipment
    Equipment is unboxed on shelves.
    - Camera
    - Camera lens
    - Easel
  - Exhibition posters (Oversize 15)
  - Glass plate negatives in custom box, box is stamped in gold with Sipprell's name; 21 items (Box 73)
  - Interview of Clara Sipprell by Vivian Perlis, 30 Dec 1971; sipprell_c_001; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 72)
    Gift of Antje Lemke, 1979
    Use copy on audiocassette in box with tape.
  - [Interview] Clara Sipprell to Phyllis Fenner in Manchester VT in their home, 1960; sipprell_c_002; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 72)
    Gift of Antje Lemke, 1980
  - Photograph, unidenfified woman, Sep 1895 (Box 70)
  - Photographs, candid shots of places and people, including Sipprell and others (Box 70)
  - Vermont Governor Award, 1974; includes invitation card (Box 70)
  - Miscellaneous, includes Hong Kong trip itinerary, interview excerpt (Box 70)
- Negatives and proof prints
  Items in freezer boxes (denoted by "FB" prefix) are not accessible to researchers.
  Glass plate negatives are currently out for digitization and not accessible to staff or researchers.
  All negatives and proof prints have been digitized. Many of the negatives also exist as prints (see Photographs below).
  The following list summarizes all negatives and proof prints in the collection, listed alphabetically by subject of the photograph whether person, place, or thing. For each subject, negatives are listed first followed by proof prints. Names are given as written on the item. For names that are illegible, incomplete, or incorrect, staff have attempted to correct/identify; this added information is given in square brackets, for example "[Kellogg], Lida and Lois [Maury] in the garden". At the end of the list are individuals whose last name is unknown, followed by unidentified items.
  - Abell, Mrs. Charles, 1957
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Abrams, Mrs. A.J., 1956
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Abreus, Egmont
    - Negatives (Box FB076)
  - Achelis, Elizabeth
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Adamic, Louis
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB076)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Adams, Austin and son Buddy, 1937
    - Negatives (Box FB077)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Adams, Austin L. and son
    - Negatives (Box FB077)
  - Adams, Buddy (Austin Adams' son)
    - Negatives (Box FB077)
  - Adams, Mrs. Crosby (Montreal - N.C. "Home in the Woods")
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Adams, Helen and Mary Singleton
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Adams, Mrs. John and baby and 4 generations Mauris-Kellogg
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Adams, Mrs. Madge A., Mrs. Edwin O. Baker, Mrs. Davenport Lowry
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Adams, Mr. and Mrs. Ralph
    - Negatives (Box FB077)
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Adams-Linn, Mrs. John (Mrs. Richard Maury)
    See also Maury, Mrs. Richard (daughter), at Linn Adams' christening.
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Adler, Dr. Felix
    - Negatives (Box FB186)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Aforn, Mrs. James A.
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Agnetti, Senator (Florence, Italy)
    - Negatives (Box FB186)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Agnew, Dricka, 1964
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Agnew, Dr. and Mrs. Hobart, 1957
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Agnew, Mrs. Hobart (daughter), 1956
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Ahn, Miss (Korean dancer, Prof. Wang)
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
  - Aiken, George, 1956
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
  - Aiken, George (Governor of Vermont)
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
  - Albert, Mrs. and daughter Susan, 1934
    - Negatives (Box 49)
  - Albert, Mrs. Little (Williams)
    - Glass plate negative, broken (Box 69-02)
  - Aldrich, Donald
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Aldrich, Susanne (daughter of Donald Aldrich)
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Allee, Mrs. E.E. (Ohio)
    - Negatives (Box FB001)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Altbery, Brita
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Alwond, Mrs. Thomas R. (The Sevilla, 117 W. 58th St.)
    - Negatives (Box FB078)
    - Negatives (Box FB079)
  - Amatum, Lilly, 1952
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
  - Ames, Margaret (Castine, Maine), 1965
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Ames, Professor A. (children)
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Anderson, Barbara (Thetford?)
    - Negatives (Box FB079)
  - Anderson, Carl (children)
    - Negatives (Box FB079)
  - Anderson, Erik (bride), 1959
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Anderson, Dr. Meta
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Anderson, Dr. and Mrs. R.C.
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Anderson, Steel
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
  - Andonian, Jeanne, 1961
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
  - Andreff, Sasha
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Apache Trail, 1929
    - Negatives (Box 58)
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Negatives (Box FB182)
  - Apple
    - Negatives (Box FB079)
  - Appleton, ---- (daughter of Mr. Leroy Appleton)
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Appleton, Mr. Leroy
    - Negatives (Box FB079)
  - Appleton, Mrs.
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - d'Archiarede [Archimede?], Rome
    - Negatives (Box FB188)
  - Arkwel, Bartlett
    - Negatives (Box FB079)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Arlington, Vermont, 1936
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Armstrong, Bishop J. Gillespie, 1959
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Negatives (Box FB154)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Arnold, Mrs. D.C., 1953
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
  - Assogioli, Dr. (Rome)
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Astori, William
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
  - Ataloa
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
  - Aubeck, Mrs. John, 1956
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
  - Austin, Mr. Harold J.
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Austin, Mrs.
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
    - Proof prints (Box 80)
  - Austin, Warren, 1956
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Ayer, Katherine
    - Negatives (Box FB002)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Babbott, Mrs. Frank
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
  - Babbott, Mrs. Frank, 1956
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Babbott, Mrs. Frank (2 daughters), 1966
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
  - Babbott, Mrs. Frank (13 year old daughter), 1939
    - Negatives (Box FB080)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Babbott, Elizabeth, 1956
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bacon, ---- (niece of Mr. Bacon)
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bafforts, Mrs. Frank (daughters in costume)
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bailey, Alice Ann
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
  - Baiz, Marguerite, 1967
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
  - Baldwin, Mrs. W.H.
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Ball, Mr. and Mrs. Rea
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Ball, Mr. and Mrs. Rea, 50th wedding anniversary
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
  - Barbier, Mr. and Mrs. J., 1963
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Barlow Wedding (Woodstock, VT, Togo Hill), July 6, 1940
    - Negatives (Box FB003)
  - Barnhart, Harry, 1st sitting
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
  - Barns in winter
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
  - Barrett, ---- (son of William F. Barrett)
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Barrett, Dr.
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB149)
  - Bartholomei, Miss Olga (Milfoil Cottage, Manor Grounds, Ashville NC)
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bates, ---- (son and family of Mrs. Bates)
    - Negatives (Box FB081)
  - Bates, Joseph
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bates, Mrs. Joseph
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
  - Baumart, William, 1944
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
  - Bayard, Clifford and family, 1940
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bayne, Mr. Howard
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bayse, Barbara (daughter of Professor Arthur Bayse), 1934
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - [Bayse?] Besyes, Barbara (daughter of Professor Arthur H. Besyes [Bayse?]), 1941
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Beardsley, Mrs. William (wedding)
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Beel, Mrs. W.H.
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Beel, Harriet (daughter of Mrs. W. H. Beel)
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Beers, Jessica E.
    - Negatives (Box FB196)
  - Beers, Jessica E. and Clara E. Sipprell, Paris
    - Negatives (Box 49)
    - Negatives (Box 63)
    - Negatives (Box FB198)
  - Belcher, Hilda
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
  - Bell, Mrs. T.W. (Sue), 1950
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bell, Mrs. William K.
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bell, Mrs. William T.
    - Negatives (Box FB004)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bellamy, Jane (wedding, Kittery Point, ME), 8/29/1953
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Negatives (Box FB083)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bellamy, Rufus and Jane
    - Negatives (Box FB082)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bellamy, Mrs. Frank
    - Negatives (Box FB083)
  - Bellows, Reynold and son Stephen
    - Negatives (Box FB083)
    - Negatives (Box FB019)
    - Proof prints (Box 76)
  - Bellows, Stephen (son of Reynold Bellows)
    - Negatives (Box FB083)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bellport
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
    - Negatives (Box FB150)
    - Negatives (Box 49)
  - Bender, Beverly, 1955
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
  - Benett, Mr. and Mrs. Felton
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bennet, Malvina, 1931
    - Negatives (Box FB083)
  - Bennett, Miss M. [Malvina?]
    - Negatives (Box FB196)
  - Bennett, Mrs. Otto
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
  - Bennett, Stewart, 1961
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bennington, Mr. Dennis
    - Negatives (Box FB083)
    - Proof prints (Box 81)
  - Bennington, Mrs. James Eddy
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Berk, Juliene, 1958
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
  - Bernadotte, Folke, Count and Countess [Estelle]
    - Negatives (Box FB103)
  - Berns, Mr. and Mrs. Joel, 1970
    - Negatives (Box FB005)
    - Proof prints (Box 74)
  - Bernstein, Mrs. Milton, 1936
    - Negatives (Box FB084)
  - Berresford